我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
killed by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度
But secretly, I use my speed
打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的人
to fight crime and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
让我父亲沉冤得雪
and get justice for my father.
我就是闪电侠
I am the flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on the flash...
是你杀了我妈妈  为什么
You killed my mother. Why?
如果你想知道原因  先追上我再说
If you want to know that, you're gonna have to catch me.
不够快  闪电侠
Not fast enough, Flash.
我爱你  爱瑞丝
I love you, Iris.
没法再瞒下去了
I couldn't lie to you anymore.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen.
我不是现今世上速度最快的人
I am not the fastest man alive.
这个名号属于杀了我妈妈的那个人
That title belongs to the man who killed my mother.
但不会太久
But not for long.
刚才太危险了
That was too close.
他告诉我要下狠手的
He told me to make it hard.
他那意思肯定不是让你弄死他
Pretty sure he didn't tell you to make him dead.
请记得  这应该只是一次
Remember, this is just supposed to be
提升巴里速度的训练
a training exercise to improve Barry's speed.
西斯科  你到底玩不玩了
Cisco, you gonna bring it or what?
上吧
Bring it.
他干嘛不跑开
Why isn't he running away?
巴里  快跑开
Barry, run away.
厉害啊  艾伦先生
Very impressive, Mr. Allen.
你在超速度下
Your reaction to stimuli
对刺激的反应速度越来越快了
at super-speed continues to improve.
-还不够快  -会够的
- It's still not enough. - It will be.
你继续像这样努力  继续这样集中精力
You keep working like you are, you stay focused like you are,
下一次那位穿黄衣服的人出现
and you will be ready the next time
你就准备好可以应对了
your man in the yellow suit comes around.
我想你说的是逆闪电
I think you mean the Reverse-Flash.
怎么  他自己说的  不是我取的
What? He said it, not me.
而且他说的没错
And he's right.
黄衣服  红色闪电  又邪恶
Yellow suit, red lightning, and evil--
巴里的反面
The reverse of Barry.
其实我觉得不错
Actually, I kind of like it.
好了  我准备好再来一场了
All right, I'm still ready for another round.
你还剩多少台无人机
How many more drones do you have left?
两台
Two.
而且它们都可以发射激光
And they've got lasers.
不行
No.
跟你说了会碎的
Told you it would break.
心理医生还说我疯了呢
And the shrink says I'm crazy.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
海关仓库
Customs warehouse.
欧洲进口车  都很值钱
Imported cars from europe, all worth a fortune.
提问
Question.
你说咱俩怎么才能
How do you suggest you and I
把这些车开出去呢
drive all these cars out of here?
不用开
We're not.
我们不偷任何东西
We're not stealing anything.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
咱们的闯入触发了无声警报
Our entrance set off the silent alarms.
警察会在
The cops will be arriving
两分十四秒之后到达
in 2 minutes and 14 seconds.
烤了他们
Bring them.
那不是为警察准备的  我们说过的
That's not for the cops, as we discussed.
他会来的
He'll be here.
你听到了  对吧
You do hear that, right?
他没来
He's not coming.
咱们走
We're leaving.
你最好能趁早给出个合理解释  伙计
This better make sense real fast, buddy.
会给的  走吧
It will. Let's go.
你保证我可以发挥我的特长的
You promised me I'd get to do my thing.
我总是信守承诺的
I always keep my promises.
系好安全带
Seat belt.
闪电侠
你确定什么都没丢吗
Are you sure nothing's missing?
管理员就是这么说的
That's what the supervisor said.
我可以再检查一遍
I can check again.
巴里
Barry.
这种破坏表明了门在
Well, the breakage indicates that the door somehow
摔到地上的时候完全没有黏弹性
had zero viscoelasticity when it hit the ground.
你能讲得通俗点吗
What does that mean to normal people?
抱歉
Sorry.
钢铁像玻璃一样破碎了
The steel shattered like glass.
它被冻上了  乔
It was frozen, Joe.
史纳特
Snart.
他回来了
He's back.
史纳特不是绝世大盗吗
I thought Snart was some world-class thief.
这么多豪车  他居然一辆都没偷走
All these expensive cars he didn't take any of them?
这说不通啊
It doesn't make sense.
艾迪  全境通缉史纳特
Eddie, put out an APB on Snart.
好的
Got it.
史纳特不是来偷东西的
Snart wasn't here to steal anything.
-他是来设陷阱的  -给我设陷阱
- He was setting a trap. - For me.
-我指的是...  -我知道你指的是谁
- And by me, I mean... - Yeah, I know who you meant.
你真美
God, you're beautiful.
米克
Mick.
这是个玩笑而已
This is a joke.
你怎么知道这个闪电侠没出城呢
How do you know this Flash didn't skip town?
说不定这就是他没现身的原因
Maybe that's why he didn't show up.
也有可能他死了
Or maybe he's dead.
也许有比你更聪明的人把他冻死了
Or maybe someone smarter than you iced him.
他没死  也没出城
He's not dead, and he didn't leave town.
你要告诉我这回我们要干什么
You will tell me what we're stealing this time.
我们是搭档
We are partners, after all.
我们就是为这个而来
This is what we came for.
《火与冰》被中城拉瑟威夫妇以2500万买下
这能值钱吗
That's worth money?
《火与冰》被中城拉瑟威夫妇以2500万买下
这幅画叫《火与冰》
It's called Fire & Ice,
是一副现代抽象派的美术杰作
an abstract modern-day masterpiece
据说是对分法的完美代表
said to represent the dichotomy of being.
对我来说这东西的意义就是
It represents to me
有钱人品位真奇怪
that people with lots of money buy dumb stuff.
奥斯古德和瑞秋·拉瑟威
Osgood and Rachel Rathaway,
中城最富有的夫妻之一
one of the richest couples in Central City,
在巴黎花了2500万买下它
paid 25 million for it in Paris.
他们今天带着画飞回来
They're flying home with it today.
寒冷队长回来了
Captain Cold is back?
作为一个非超能力者
For a non-metahuman,
莱昂纳多·史纳特还真是不好对付
Leonard Snart is proving to be quite the nemesis.
冷冻枪还在他手上
He still has the cold gun,
他从我们手里夺走的  这是我的设计
the one he stole from us, the one I built.
这回他又想干什么
Well, what does he want this time?
他要的是闪电侠
The Flash.
如果史纳特想跟闪电侠打一场
If Snart wants a fight with the Flash,
我就跟他打一场
then I'll give him one.
你觉得我不该这样做
You don't think I should?
我没这么说  不过巴里
I didn't say that. But, Barry,
就算你速度够快  你也不可能处处兼顾
as fast as you are, you cannot be everywhere at once.
这就演变成哪个优先的问题
And it becomes then a question of priorities.
过去的一个月里
Now, in the last month,
你努力要提高速度
you have made a commitment to increasing your speed,
加强反应能力  一切都井井有条
enhancing your reflexes, and it's working.
你终于变得更快了
You're finally getting faster.
那我要怎么做  不管史纳特吗
Okay, but what am I supposed to do, just ignore Snart?
你上回跟史纳特斗争时  一列火车脱轨了
The last time you had a fight with Snart, a train derailed.
能把所有人救回来是你运气好
You were lucky to get all those people to safety.
如果你不跟他打的话
And if you don't give him that fight...
他可能会自己离开  不会有任何伤亡
He may just back off, and there'll be no casualties.
巴里  西斯科和我会跟乔
Look, Barry, Cisco and I will work with Joe
还有警方合作  想出办法抓到寒冷队长
and the police and devise a way to catch Cold.
没错  我就是这么说的  西斯科
Yes, I said it, Cisco.
话脱口而出的时候我就听到了
As soon as it came out of my mouth, I heard it.
我们一定会想出办法
Yeah, we can definitely come up with ways
拿下史纳特的
to neutralize Snart.
巴里
Listen, Barry.
不管你去不去追查史纳特  这都是你的选择
Whether or not you go after Snart, that's your choice.
我们会尽一切可能帮助你
We here, we will do whatever we can to support you.
但经过这次圣诞节
But after this past Christmas,
在出了逆闪那事之后
after the events with the Reverse-Flash...
我觉得他给所有人都造成了更大的威胁
I just think he poses a greater threat to all of us.
离意义非凡的同居生活
T-minus three days and counting...
还有三天
till the big move in.
我从没有过室友
You know, I've never had a roommate.
不过我发现  如果我们吵架了
But it did occur to me that if we ever get in a fight,
我不能发泄一通就回自己家
I can't just storm away and go home,
因为到时候那就是我们的家了
because home will be with you.
你已经预料到我们会吵架了
Are you predicting many arguments?
你没见过我吗
Have you met me?
我记得我们相遇的那晚
I remember the night we met.
我抓住了偷你包的抢劫犯
I stopped a mugger who stole your bag.
我的英雄
My hero.
艾迪  你知道乔在哪里吗
Eddie, you know where Joe is?
他应该在楼上你的实验室里
I think he's upstairs in your lab.
谢谢
Okay, thanks.
同居的事情不用再考虑一下吗
No second thoughts about moving in together?
不用了
None.
乔  你好
Joe, hey.
很高兴你回来了
I'm glad you're back.
我在看史纳特的档案
I've been going over Snart's file.
谢谢  我得跟你谈谈
Thanks. Yeah, I need to talk to you.
作为犯罪现场鉴证员
As CSI,
我在这案子的工作已经结束了
my work on this case is done.
作为闪电侠
And as the Flash,
我现在没法把精力放在史纳特身上
I don't think I can focus on Snart right now.
介不介意告诉我是什么
You mind telling me what brought about
让你改变主意了
this change of heart?
这个穿黄衣服的  杀了我妈妈的人
This man in yellow, the man that killed my mom,
还逍遥法外
is still out there.
我必须做好应对他的准备
I have to be ready to face him,
那就意味着我要提升我的速度
which means amping up my speed.
-这是哪个优先的问题  -抓捕凶手
- It's a question of priorities. - Your mom's killer
并不是你做这件事的唯一原因
isn't the only reason you've been doing this.
你告诉过我  如果可以用你的能力
You told me that if you could use your powers
从起火的大楼里救人  你会做的
to save someone from a burning building, you would.
威尔斯博士和尖端科研实验室的人会跟你合作
Look, Dr. Wells and S.T.A.R. Labs are gonna work with you.
西斯科认为他有办法
Cisco thinks he has a way
可以让警察不受史纳特冷冻枪的攻击
to protect the police against Snart's cold gun.
巴里  如果你害怕  我可以理解
Barry, I can understand if you're scared.
-我们谈过这个的  -我当然害怕  乔
- We talked about this. - Of course I'm scared, Joe.
这家伙可能会冲进警局来
This guy could run into the precinct
在几秒钟内杀死所有的人
and kill everyone in here in seconds.
他威胁过爱瑞丝
He threatened Iris.
我不会让他再一次伤害我生命中
I won't let him hurt the most important people
最重要的人
in my life again.
如果那意味着我要牺牲所有时间
If that means devoting every second
离开这里去提升我的速度来阻止他
I have outside this place to getting faster and to stopping him,
那我就会去做的
then that's what I'm gonna do.
对不起  我已经决定了
I'm sorry. I've made up my mind.
乌龟迈克施纳特
Mcsnurtle the turtle.
你怎么样
How you been?
你什么时候开始不搂着它睡觉的
When did you stop sleeping with this?
-它是你的最爱  -没错
- It was your favorite. - He was.
可是如果我没记错的话
But if I remember correctly,
我把你艾灵顿公爵那张《蓝调之音》的
you took him away from me after I broke your Duke Ellington:
黑胶唱片弄碎以后  你就把它夺走了
Live at the Blue Note vinyl.
是的
Oh, yeah.
-现在可以还给你了  -老天  谢谢
- You can have him back now. - Oh, gee, thanks.
爸爸
Oh, dad.
我会想你的  宝贝
I'm going to miss you, baby.
爸爸  只要十分钟就到我那了
Dad, I'm only ten minutes away.
我知道  你不用担心我
I know. Don't you worry about me.
我会好好的  跟以前一样
I'll be fine, just like always.
-好啊  -好啊
- Hey. - Hey.
你来帮她收拾行李的吗
You came to help her pack?
不  不是
Oh, no. No, no, no.
爱瑞丝说有东西要给我
Iris said that she had something for me.
我在柜子里找到了这个
I found this in my closet.
已经好多年没看到它了
I haven't seen this in years.
宅男必备单品依然完好无损
Well, the nerd survival kit is still intact.
我想那些东西可能值得你珍藏
I thought those might be worth something.
《太空大侠之天上地下唯我是听》
我要迟到了
I am so late for work.
我保证回来以后会收拾干净的  好吗
I promise I will clean this up when I get back, okay?
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye, yeah.
好吧
Okay.
能告诉我你和爱瑞丝之间发生什么了吗
You mind telling me what's going on with you and Iris?
没什么
Nothing.
真有趣  因为我脸上有两个叫做眼睛的东西
That's funny, because I have these two things called eyes,
而你们俩看起来并不好
and it doesn't look like you two are fine.
我告诉爱瑞丝了
I told Iris.
你告诉爱瑞丝你是闪电侠了
You told Iris you're the Flash?
不  不是
No, no, no, no. I'm sorry.
不是
No.
我跟她说了我的感觉
I told her how I felt about her.
天呐
Oh, god.
她说什么了
What did she say?
结果她还是要搬去跟艾迪一起住  不是吗
Well, I mean, she's still moving in with Eddie, isn't she?
我只是想装作什么事都没发生过
I just want to pretend like it never even happened.
我们俩都是这样想的  所以...
I mean, that's what we're both doing, so...
刚开始你就应该说出自己的感受
Well, not saying how you feel is what got you
否则不会到今天这个地步
in this mess in the first place.
说到这
Speaking of which,
我们都知道她不可能回来收拾的吧
we both know she's not gonna clean this mess up anytime soon.
没错
Nope.
好吧
Sure.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
请大家注意听我说
If I could have everybody's attention, please.
我们在听呢  拉蒙先生
You have our attention, Mr. Ramon.
好的  看这个
Okay, check it.
威尔斯博士和我
So Dr. Wells and I,
我们拿走了你们的防弹盾牌
we took your ballistic shields and--
在上面加了密集的绝缘线
and we lined them with a pretty sweet compacted heating ribbon
用来抵挡温度带来的袭击
designed to repel temperature attacks,
尤其是那些接近绝对零度的武器
especially those reaching absolute zero,
比如寒冷队长的枪
like Captain Cold's gun.
那个就能防止我们
And that's supposed to keep us from getting
-被冻成冰棍了吗  -是的
- turned into popsicles? - Yeah.
是的  它们可以
Yeah, they will.
我们怎么还能相信尖端科研实验室的东西
How are we supposed to trust anything from S.T.A.R. Labs
在你们用核武器摧毁了这座城市后
after you nuked the city?
你说得对
You're right.
你说得对  你们不该相信我们
You're right, you shouldn't trust us.
一年前发生的事  是我们的错
What happened a year ago-- that was our fault.
我们不能改变过去发生的事
And we can't change the past,
尽管我们非常想
as much as we wish we could.
但未来就不同了
But tomorrow is a different story.
未来是另一回事了
Tomorrow's a different thing.
我们只希望有让一切变好的机会
We just want the chance to make things better.
仔细看吧
Observe.
模型是模型
Dummies are one thing.
我的警官们可是另一回事
My officers are another.
你看上去对自己很满意  博士
You seem pleased with yourself, doctor.
我只是很高兴能帮助警察抓史纳特  乔
Well, I'm just happy to help the police catch Snart, Joe.
巴里或许也能帮上忙
Barry might be able to help too.
我认为西斯科的热盾牌
I think Cisco's heat shields
已经能胜任这个任务了
are more than up to the task.
乔  如果巴里觉得他去追捕史纳特
And, Joe, if Barry feels he's gonna endanger lives
会危机其他人的生命  相反地
by taking on Snart and, conversely, feels
训练速度去追捕
he's gonna save lives by training
穿黄色衣服的人能拯救生命的话
to take on the man in yellow...
那完全是他自己的意愿
That's ultimately his call.
你知道是什么让巴里这么特别吗
You know what makes Barry so special?
他想帮助所有他能帮助的人
He wants to help everyone he can,
不管以什么方式
however he can.
他都会去做的
Always has.
可现在变了
Until now.
我想只是优先排序的问题
I guess it's just a question of priorities then.
巴里跟我说了一模一样的话
You know, Barry said the exact same thing to me.
我当时想  这不像是他说得话
And I thought, "Doesn't sound like him."
我想是因为听上去像是你会说的话
I guess because it sounds like you.
抱歉  没想吓你的
Sorry, didn't mean to scare you.
不  没关系  我只是太投入了
No, it's okay. I was just kind of focused.
懂了
Gotcha.
-什么是火风暴  -是罗尼飞走前
- What's F.I.R.E.S.T.O.R.M.? - It's one of the last things
最后跟我说的话
Ronnie said to me before he... flew away.
我死去的未婚夫会飞
My dead fiance can fly.
我还没跟我父母透露过这个
I haven't broke that to my parents yet.
-你还好吧  -好  还好
- You doing okay? - Yeah, yeah.
不  我只是
No, I just...
我告诉爱瑞丝我对她的感觉了
I told Iris how I felt about her.
大胆的选择
Bold choice.
我知道我们之前的关系
I knew where we stood before.
我们是最好的朋友
We were best friends.
我不知道  现在我不知道
And...I don't know. Now I just don't know
我们之间正常的关系应该是怎么样了
what's normal for us anymore.
在我遇到罗尼前
Before I met Ronnie,
我知道我的生活中将会发生什么
I knew exactly what was going to happen every day of my life.
是可预测的  我喜欢可预测
It was predictable. I like predictable.
但当罗尼和我开始约会后
But when Ronnie and I started dating,
一切都开始变了
everything started to change.
他让我尝试印度食物
He made me try Indian food
以及水肺潜水
and SCUBA diving.
一开始我很害怕
At first it was scary.
但是后来就好了
But then it was better.
你对爱瑞丝的爱慕而她却毫不知情
Things weren't really normal with you pining after Iris
这本就不正常
and her being totally unaware.
不管接下来会发生什么  都会更好
Whatever happens next, it will be better.
等等  凯特琳
Wait, Caitlin.
水肺
SCUBA.
怎么了
What about it?
自给式水下呼吸器
Self-contained underwater breathing apparatus,
是缩写
it's an acronym.
如果火风暴不是一个词呢
What if F.I.R.E.S.T.O.R.M. isn't a word?
原始核糖核酸及分子结构转变的
Fusion ignition research experiment and science
聚变点火试验和科学研究
of transmutation originating RNA and molecular structures.
有八百页
It's 800 pages.
里面写了很多东西
There's a lot of stuff in there,
但大部分讲的是转变
but it mostly focuses on transmutation,
就是通过解压原子
which is the process of altering the structure of an element
改变元素结构
by unzipping the atoms--
并重构一个新元素的过程
and rebuilding it to create an entirely new element.
这篇文章是由杰森·拉什合作编写的
Well, the article was co-written by Jason Rush,
杰森·拉什是三代火风暴
他是休斯敦大学的一名研究生
who's a grad student here at Hudson university.
所以如果有谁知道罗尼发生了什么的话
So if anybody knows what happened to Ronnie...
或许他知道
Maybe he does.
-也许吧  -谢谢
- Maybe. - Thanks.
旅途愉快吗  拉瑟威夫人
Pleasant flight, Mrs. Rathaway?
很愉快  谢谢
Yes, quite. Thank you.
请小心点  值一大笔钱呢
Careful, please. It's worth a fortune.
欢迎回家  拉瑟威先生
Welcome home, Mr. Rathaway.
谢谢你  伊森
Thank you, Ethan.
老爷  你儿子哈特利又打电话来了
Sir, your son Hartley-- he called again.
我们已经没有儿子了
We don't have a son anymore.
最好有人打报警电话
Someone better call 911.
走  快走
Move. Move!
史纳特  别动
Snart, freeze.
米克
Mick!
搞什么
What the hell?
他们为何叫你们热火
Why do they call you people the heat?
我才是热火
I'm the heat!
别管他们了  米克  准备好迎接他
Forget them, Mick. Get ready for him.
这太美了
It's beautiful.
米克
Mick.
Mick!
我们现在就撤
We go, now!
他没事吧
Is he all right?
好的
Okay.
你没事吧
Hey. Hey, are you okay?
我晚点再打给你
I'll call you back.
我没事
I'm fine.
史纳特的新同伙
Snart's new partner,
有一个手拿式喷火器
he's got this handheld flamethrower.
基本上所有人都当场得到了救治  但...
Almost everyone was treated on the scene, but...
还是有两个人进了烧伤病房
we got two in the burn unit, though.
对不起  我应该听你的
I'm sorry. I should've listened to you.
没事  但是
It's all good. But...
下次史纳特和他的火焰兵伙伴再出现
the next time Snart and his pyro pal show up,
你让他们为跟你作对而抱歉
you make them sorry they ever messed with you.
我要给医院打电话了
I got to call the hospital.
警察的子弹打坏了第二个内燃料枪膛
The cop's bullet ruptured the secondary internal fuel chamber.
本可能会更坏
It could've been worse.
还好你让我学这玩意的
You were right to get me to learn
每一个部分和线路
every part and circuit of this thing.
修理这个就是
Repairing it was...
弹指一挥间
a snap.
立刻给我一个
Give me one reason
不杀你的理由
I don't kill you right now.
再找一个听你讲
It's gonna be hard to find
胜利演说的人比较难
someone else to listen to your winning speeches.
你刚才失控了  就像上次一样
You lost it out there, just like the last job.
你失去了重心  开始沉沦
You lost focus, became obsessed.
我沉沦  那你呢
I'm obsessed? What about you?
你总是精确时间  规划好所有事
You're usually counting the seconds, got the whole thing
细致地一丝不苟
planned out, dotting "T"s, crossing "I"s.
但你现在只关心闪电侠
But all you care about now is the Flash.
-我们要除掉他  -为什么
- We have to put him down. - Why?
我们拿到了手指画
We got the finger painting.
这值上百万  这是我们的了
It's worth millions. It's ours.
我们有钱了  收工
We're rich. Job done.
那之后的任务呢  米克
And what about the next job, Mick?
之后的之后呢
And the job after that?
有了这样的武器
With weapons like these,
没人能对抗我们  除了闪电侠
no one can stand against us, no one except the Flash.
如果你想退出  就拿着画走吧
If you want out, take the painting and go.
但如果你想将中城变成我们
But if you want Central City to be our home where we can do
想拿什么就拿什么的大本营
and take whatever we want...
这是我们的机会
this is our chance...
你的机会
Your chance.
非常鼓舞人心
Very motivational.
我们怎么抓到他
How do we get him?
闪电侠跟我们无异
The Flash isn't so different from us.
他也有同伴
He's got partners too.
杰森·拉什
Jason Rush?
我是  斯诺博士吗
Yes. Dr. Snow?
请叫我凯特琳  谢谢你来见我
Please, call me Caitlin. Thank you for meeting me.
乐意之极
Oh, happy to.
但是  提前声明
Although, to be totally up front,
如果这有关我递给尖端科研实验室的简历
if this is about the resume I mailed in to S.T.A.R. Labs,
我已经在水星实验室就职了
I've already accepted a position at Mercury Labs.
其实不是的  我想跟你聊下火风爆的事
No, actually, I wanted to talk to you about Firestorm.
不好意思  你弄错了  我该走了
I'm sorry. This was a mistake. I have to go.
不  我关心的人正有麻烦
No, look, someone I care about is in trouble,
而你是我唯一能帮到他的线索
and you're the only clue I have to help him.
拜托了
Please.
什么情况
What's the line?
他们开始暗算我之前  我不是这样多疑的
I never got paranoid till they started plotting against me?
他们为什么要暗算你
Why would they be plotting against you?
因为我们的成果  因为火风爆
Because of our work, because of Firestorm.
转变
Transmutation,
是在分子层面上转变物质的能力
the ability to alter matter on a molecular level.
在使用砂砾的情况下
We had some rudimentary success
我们在第一步测试中有了微小的成功
with our stage one testing, working with sand grains.
但是斯泰因教授说我们应该...
But Professor Stein said that we should--
不好意思  马丁·斯泰因教授
Sorry, Professor Martin Stein?
马丁·斯泰因是初代火风暴合体者之一
他也是文献作者之一
He was the co-author of the paper?
是  他是我们的组长
Yeah, he was our team leader.
他不相信小成功  所以我们跳至第三步
He didn't believe in baby steps, so we skipped to stage three.
那是...
Which was?
我们融化了一堵钢筋混凝土墙
We melted a concrete wall.
但学校威胁要关闭我们
But the university threatened to shut us down.
所以斯泰因教授
So Professor Stein
在没经过他们允许的情况下发表了文章
published his paper without them giving permission,
然后他们就气疯了
and they went nuts.
所以他就去找他的一个朋友
So he went to talk to a friend of his
-来确保私下支持  -他是谁
- to secure private backing. - And who was that?
他没说  他只说晚点打给我
He didn't say. He just said he'd call me later.
在那之后斯泰因教授就下落不明了
And no one has seen or heard from Professor Stein since.
你觉得他发生了什么事
What do you think happened to him?
我只知道第二天军队来了
All I know is that the army showed up the next day
并且没收了我们的一切研究
and confiscated all of our research.
斯诺博士  告诉我  你觉得我太偏执
So tell me, Dr. Snow, do you think I'm being too paranoid,
还是不够偏执
or not paranoid enough?
马丁·斯泰因教授失踪
车子坏了吗
Car trouble?
但愿我们不是敌人
I hope we're not enemies.
什么  当然不是
What? No, of course not.
我以为你可能会埋怨我
I thought you might blame me
逼你继续训练
for pushing you to pursue your training
而不让你去帮助警察
rather than help the police.
我是个成年人
Look, I'm an adult.
我自己做出选择  自己承担责任
I make my own choices, my own mistakes.
而且很高兴你让我变得更好
And I'm glad you push me to be better.
感觉很奇怪
It's so weird.
在我一生中曾经有一段时间
There was a time in my life
我会付钱买你的亲笔签名
that I would've paid money for your autograph.
而现在我们却是...
And now we're...
搭档了
Partners.
我想说朋友的
I was gonna say friends.
如果你怀疑  你也让我变得更好
In case you doubt it, you push me to be better too.
你们得过来看看这个
Guys, you have to come look at this.
当热风枪发射时
When the Heat Gun was fired,
它使周围空气的温度大幅增加了
it increased the surrounding temperature of the air
就像是一股异常的热浪来袭
dramatically, sort of like an extreme heat wave.
-热浪哦  -别再这么做
- Heat Wave. - Stop doing that.
好吧  我已经测量过冷冻枪
Okay. I measured the temperature output
和热风枪的输出温度
of both the Cold and Heat Guns, right?
当冷冻枪达到绝对零度时
And while the Cold Gun achieves absolute zero,
热风就能成功地达到绝对热度
the Heat Gun successfully reaches absolute hot,
或是物体所能达到的最热温度
or the hottest temperature an object can reach.
-普朗克温度  -非常有可能
- Planck temperature. - So potentially,
这两种枪也能相互抵消
these two guns could cancel each other out.
但要做到这点  你得让两枪相互交流
Yeah, but to do that, you'd have to make them cross streams.
就像是《驱鬼者》吗
You mean like Ghostbusters?
那部电影可是非常地科学准确
That film is surprisingly scientifically accurate.
其实挺好看的
And really quite funny.
乔  什么事
Hey, Joe. What's up?
乔  有发现吗
Joe, anything?
没有凯特琳的踪迹
There's no sign of Caitlin.
我们要把她救回来的  要找到史纳特
We're getting her back. We have to find Snart.
绝对的
Damn right we do.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
乔  乔
Joe, Joe.
有线索了  这是第二组指纹
We got a hit, a second pair of prints.
是米克·罗里的
They belong to a Mick Rory.
-他是谁  -一流纵火犯
- Who is he? - Big-time arsonist.
去年他和史纳特的一单交易黄了
He and Snart worked a job last year that went bad.
罗里的一半身体被火烧伤
Half of Rory's body was burned in a fire
无法自控
that got out of control.
在去医院的路上  他逃离了救护车
He escaped from an ambulance on the way to the hospital,
到现在都毫无踪影
hasn't been seen since.
他们为什么要绑架凯特琳
Why would they kidnap someone like Caitlin?
乔  斯旺  每个台都在播
Joe, Thawne, it's on every station.
中城的市民们  大家好
Greetings, citizens of Central City.
我是莱昂纳多·史纳特
I am Leonard Snart.
你们也可以叫我寒冷队长
But you can call me Cold.
我不会说得太复杂
I'm gonna make this very simple for everyone.
你们私下里谈论的那位红衣侠
That Red Streak you've been hearing whispers about,
过去几个月以来  神出鬼没拯救大众的那位
the one mysteriously saving people these past few months?
大吃一惊吧  他可是真是存在的
Well, surprise, he's real.
他自称为闪电侠
He calls himself The Flash.
火车站  今晚日落时分
Porter and main, tonight, sundown.
无论你在何处  现身吧  闪电侠
Come out, come out, wherever you are, Flash.
告诉全世界你不是虚幻的
Show the whole world you're real.
否则她就要死
Or this woman dies.
不  别来救我  别来
No, don't come for me. Stay away!
你是他的朋友吧
You're a friend of his, huh?
他的速度很快
He's fast...
就如一团火焰
like fire.
火焰可说不准啊
Fire, it's undefinable.
热量  光线  能量
Heat, light, energy.
这可是物体燃烧时的进化论
It's an evolution when things burn.
变态
You're sick.
也许你也是  你有想过这点吗
Maybe you're the sick ones. You ever think about that?
没想过
Not really.
你受过三度烧伤
You've got third-degree burns.
为什么不做皮肤移植
Why didn't you get skin grafts?
火焰展现了真实自我
The fire revealed my true self,
让我知道我到底是谁
showed me who I really am.
我想知道当我把你的闪电侠
I wonder what your Flash will reveal
烧得皮干肉净时  他会变成什么样
when I burn his suit and skin off.
随你怎么处置我  放过他
Do whatever you want to me, but leave him alone.
好吧
Oh, okay.
你愿意为这位闪电侠而死
You and this Flash must be really close
看来你和他很亲近嘛
if you're willing to die for him?
想让我展示给你看  真实的你吗
You want me to show you who you really are?
肯定很好玩
That'd be fun.
让你看看真实的自己
Show you who you... really are.
米克
Mick.
该走了
Time to go.
你最好祈祷下次
You better pray the next people
进门的人还是我们
that come through this door is us.
-喂  -万事俱备
- Hey. - Okay, you're on.
祝好运  孩子
Good luck, son.
谢谢
Thanks.
巴里  今晚之后
Barry, after tonight,
所有人都会知道闪电侠真的存在
everyone's gonna know that the Flash exists.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready for that?
回见了
I'll see you soon.
你看到了吗
Did, did you see that?
是他  是闪电侠
That was him. That was the Flash.
我不信
I don't believe it.
你还是信吧
Believe it.
红衣飞侠
The Scarlet Speedster.
想不想挑个死法
Any preference on how you'd like to die?
火焰还是冰冻
The flame or the frost?
不想聊天啊  明白了
Not in the mood for chitchat. Gotcha.
就等你了
Ready when you are.
掩护我
Cover me!
看你跑不跑的掉
Run on this.
巴里  巴里  你没事吧
Barry. Barry, are you okay?
你知道该做什么
You know what you have to do.
知道  让他们的光波相交
Yeah, get them to cross their beams
抵消枪的作用  我知道
and cancel their guns out. I know.
米克
Mick!
打中你啦
Gotcha!
做起来可没说着这么容易啊
Yeah, not as easy as it sounds.
艾迪  艾迪
Eddie, Eddie!
-爱瑞丝  你怎么来了  -疏散时
- Iris, what are you doing here? - They evacuated jitters.
-我看到了你的车  -不  你不能来
- I saw your car. - No, you can't be here.
这里不安全
It's not safe.
你确定凯特琳在这里吗  西斯科
Are you sure Caitlin's here, Cisco?
从凯特琳的车那里开始
Starting from Caitlin's car,
我拼凑起了监控录像
I pieced together surveillance footage that led us
找到了他的大概方位
to his general area.
但这里有一堆仓库啊
But there's over a dozen warehouses here.
没错  但只有一个
Yeah, but only one of them
连续三晚有暖气供应
has had the heat on the last three nights.
我想米克·罗里肯定喜欢热
And I'm betting Mick Rory likes it hot.
好吧
Okay.
待在我身后
Stay behind me.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
凯特琳  是你吗
Caitlin, is that you?
-凯特琳  -不
- Caitlin. - No!
我们马上就救你出来
We're gonna get you out of here.
西斯科  西斯科  趴下
Cisco! Cisco, down!
打斗已经蔓延到了疏散区域外了
The fight is spreading beyond the evac area.
我们得扩展疏散边界
We need to expand the perimeter.
不行  不能让这态势恶化下去了
We can't. We can't let this spread.
天呐
Oh, my God!
-斯旺  你去哪  -艾迪  艾迪
- Thawne, where are you going? - Eddie, Eddie.
斯旺
Thawne!
我以为我真的要死了
I thought I was gonna die.
有我在就不会让你死
Not while I'm around.
还有他
Or him.
坚持住
Hold on!
-我来  -小心  小心
- I got him! - Look out, look out, look out!
我没法让他们的光波交错
I can't get them to cross streams.
速度快根本没有用
Speed isn't getting it done.
你说的对
You're right.
也许要做到需要的不是速度快
Maybe the way to do this is not by going faster.
而是速度慢
It's going slower.
没错
Yes.
谢谢你的奉陪  孩子
Thanks for playing, kid.
没想到你会出这招
I didn't see that coming.
我想这回合是你赢了
I guess you win this time.
不会有下个回合了
There won't be a next time.
谢谢你  警探
Thank you, detective.
你们这些混蛋
Every last one of you pigs!
放开我
Get your hands off me!
-他搭档真是个性急的人  -真讽刺
- Partner's a real hothead. - That's funny.
你知道最让人开心的是什么吗  史纳特
You know what's hilarious, Snart?
是我们抓住了你
We got you.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
带他出去
Get him out of here.
干的好  艾迪
Nice work, Eddie.
不是我的功劳
It wasn't me.
是闪电侠
It was the Flash.
庭审的时候用不着这些了
We're not gonna be needing these for the trial.
-你要确保  -确保再没人能用它们
- You'll make sure-- - They'll never hurt anyone
伤人
ever again.
拉蒙先生
Mr. Ramon.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他就像道闪电一般划过了街道
He was like a lightning bolt, zipping through the streets.
一只手就把他们都搞定了
Took them both out singlehandedly.
-太厉害了  -我很好奇他是谁
- That's amazing. - I wonder who he is.
要是我说的话  他是个英雄
If you ask me, he's a hero.
-好的  慢点  -这是最后的了
- Okay, all right. - I think that's it.
最好是的
This better be it.
就像你说的
Well, like you said,
你离这很近  所以如果落下了什么东西
you're ten minutes away, so if you forget something...
好的
Okay.
老爸
Dad.
我就是说不够
I can't say it enough.
我会想你的
I'll miss you.
你随时都可以来的  乔
You know you can come around anytime, Joe.
提前通知我们一声就行
Just give us a heads-up.
不通知也行
Or not.
随时都可以来
Come around whenever.
你想要把钥匙吗
You want a key?
我先出去吧
I'm gonna go.
我在车里等你
I'll wait in the truck.
你们俩谈谈吧
Why don't I give you two a minute?
我知道最近
Look, I know things have been
咱们俩的关系有点不正常
really weird between us recently.
是的  确实是
Yeah, they have.
你知道我能预测未来吗
Well, did you know that I can see into the future?
-是吗  -真的
- Really? - Yeah.
我没告诉你吗
Did I forget to tell you that?
你没说过  没说过
You did not mention it, no.
那你预测到了什么
So what do you see?
我预测到你和艾迪在一起会很幸福
I see you and Eddie being really happy together.
而且我们俩的关系也会好起来
And things aren't weird between us anymore.
虽然需要一些时间  但会恢复正常的
It took a little time, but everything's back to normal,
我们还是最好的朋友
and we're still best friends.
未来也不错嘛
The future doesn't sound so bad.
是的
No.
未来很快就会来的
And it'll be here faster than you think.
老爸  我能不能...
Dad, is it okay if I...
可以
Yeah.
我的宝贝女儿
My baby girl.
再见
See you.
你还好吗
You okay?
你呢
How about you?
有些事总是要发生的  对吧
It was bound to happen sometime, right?
叫个披萨  看场比赛怎么样
Want to order some pizza and watch the ball game?
有披萨吃怎么都行
Make it pizzas and you're on.
你要是需要别人
You know, if you ever need somebody
过来帮你吃东西  我随叫随到
to come and eat your food, I'm there.
而且  我们楼里的洗衣机
Besides, the laundry machines in my building
已经坏了差不多一个月了  所以...
have been broken for, like, a month, so...
我不明白你当初为什么要搬到那个鬼地方
I don't know why you moved into that deathtrap in the first place,
你在这的房间不是很好吗
since you still got a perfectly good room here.
你说你要把它改成健身房
You said you were turning it into a gym.
咱俩都知道那是不可能的
We both know I'm not turning it into a gym.
而且
Besides,
你让我东奔西跑得也够多了
you got me running around enough as it is.
现在想要在晚上
You know, it is getting hard to hide the blasting
进出公寓时不被邻居发现
in and out of my apartment at all hours of the night
越来越难了
from my neighbors.
所以我想我应该搬回来了
I suppose it would make sense for me to move back in.
我可是千禧之子  我们这代人就是这样
I mean, I am a millennial. That is what we do.
别算上我
Well, don't do it on my account.
我自己很好
I'll be fine on my own.
是的  我也是
Oh, yeah, me too. Sure.
好了  室友  你来叫披萨吧
All right, roomie. You order the pizzas.
我去把行李拿出来
I'll unpack.
不行
No way.
我要帮你
I want to help you.
我要享受一下
I want to enjoy this.
好吧
All right.
你知道我是喝不醉的
You know this does nothing to me.
你就喝吧
Just drink it.
铁山监狱
我本应该把整座城市都烧毁了
I should've burned the entire city block down.
但我却听了你的话
But instead, I listened to you.
我们拿到了画  拿到了枪
We had the painting. We had the guns.
我们可以拥有一切
We could've had everything.
你却要执行你那愚蠢的计划
But you had your stupid plan.
现在这个计划能救我们吗
How is that stupid plan working out for us now?
现在所有人都看见闪电侠了
Everyone's seen the Flash now.
这又一次改变了情况
This changes things, again.
怎么...
What the...
史纳特
Snart!
别紧张  米克
Relax, Mick.
怎么回事
What's going on?
这就是计划
The plan.
你好  妹妹
Hey, sis.
很好
Nice.